<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CI 5371 on CI 5371</title>
    <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CI 5371 on CI 5371</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (CC BY)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/laumn/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A warm welcome to &lt;strong&gt;CI 5371 - Learning Analytics: Theory and Practice&lt;/strong&gt;! I am so excited to offer this course again this fall at the University of Minnesota. As the instructor, I learn so much from the class community each year and look forward to our adventure together this semester!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get familiar with the course, including its design, schedule, and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to know each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read an introductory article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss our diverse interests in learning analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-course&#34;&gt;The Course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing first, please read &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/laumn-2019-syl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the course syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in its entirety. Leave a comment or send me an email when you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-setup&#34;&gt;Technology setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An online course does not need to be about watching videos and answering quizzes. To foster rich learning experiences, we will be using several technological tools to foster social, collaborative learning. Depending on your familiarity with these tools, there could be a learning curve. So please spend time this week to familiarize yourself with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoom&lt;/strong&gt;. We will host a number of virtual meetings on Zoom throughout the semester. Please make sure your computer has &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; installed (see the video below). Please test your Zoom setup in advance to make sure audio and video configurations work properly. You will receive a calendar invitation with details about joining our Zoom meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vFhAEoCF7jg?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack&lt;/strong&gt;. You will receive a link that invites you to join &lt;a href=&#34;https://la-mn.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our Slack community&lt;/a&gt;. Course announcements are made on Slack. All sorts of class discussion will take place there as well. You can also interact with course alums in some public channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time using Slack? Watch the video below and/or read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/115004071768-What-is-Slack-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;brief introduction to Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9RJZMSsH7-g?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/strong&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re a formal participant, you should have received a link that invites you to join our Hypothes.is group. Hypothes.is is a web annotation tool that enables us to discuss readings in a contextual manner. When annotating, please make sure our group name (&lt;strong&gt;LAUMN-2019&lt;/strong&gt;) is properly selected. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/help/quick-start-guide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; to get started, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/help/annotating-with-groups/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; to learn about annotating together as a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://d242fdlp0qlcia.cloudfront.net/uploads/2018/03/21135305/scopeselector-groupname.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Forum&lt;/strong&gt; (KF). If you&amp;rsquo;re a formal participant, you should have received a link and a registration key to join our Knowledge Forum community. KF is a space for collaborative knowledge building. It&amp;rsquo;s where we propose our initial (and sometimes naive) ideas and then grow them this semester. KF has a suite of analytics tools as well, so it will allows us to &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; the capacity of learning analytics while we explore this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-tracks-of-participation&#34;&gt;Two tracks of participation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course website is openly available, allowing two tracks of participation designed for this class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UMN class&lt;/strong&gt;: For UMN graduate students enrolled in the class, your participation in this class is not that different from taking another online class. You are expected to meet course requirements outlined in the course syllabus. You will have &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; spaces (on Slack and Hypothesis private group) for within-class communications. You can decide the extent to which you interact with colleagues outside of the class list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open participation&lt;/strong&gt;: For &amp;lsquo;Open Participants&amp;rsquo; who would like to follow along, you can access the same materials curated on this website. Because 90% of course readings are open-access, you will be able to annotate readings using Hypothes.is as well (using &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=tag%3ALAUMN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;LAUMN&lt;/code&gt; tag&lt;/a&gt;). You are also encouraged to interact with me and community members via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23LAUMN&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter hashtag &lt;code&gt;#LAUMN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback on the design, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-1&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course syllabus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.sagepub.com.ezp3.lib.umn.edu/doi/pdf/10.1177/0002764213498851&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Siemens, G. (2013). Learning analytics: The emergence of a discipline. The American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1380–1400.&lt;/a&gt;  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://iu.instructure.com/files/56153619/download?download_frd=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Downloadable PDF&lt;/a&gt; for Open Participants.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading Siemens (2013), &lt;strong&gt;please create at least 1 annotation and reply to 2 annotations made by peers&lt;/strong&gt;. Not sure what/how to annotate, consider sentence starters like: &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;m intrigued by...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;m surprised by...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I need to understand...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Additional resource...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Click on the Annotations link to the top of this page to see all annotations posted to our Hypothes.is group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-meeting&#34;&gt;Virtual Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first virtual meeting will take place on &lt;strong&gt;Monday, 09/09, 5-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; via Zoom. You will receive a Calendar invitation with details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotations</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://hypothes.is/groups/a3ZVxWe8/laumn-2019&#34; width = &#34;100%&#34; height = &#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
