<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CI 5371 on CI 5371</title>
    <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CI 5371 on CI 5371</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (CC BY)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/laumn/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/glossary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe name=&#34;embed_readwrite&#34; src=&#34;https://etherpad.net/p/LAUMN-Glossary?showControls=true&amp;showChat=true&amp;showLineNumbers=true&amp;useMonospaceFont=false&#34; width = &#34;100%&#34; height = &#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Ethics, Algorithmic Accountability, and System Integrity</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be clear, &lt;em&gt;ethics&lt;/em&gt; should not be an after-thought in a learning analytics application. But what do ethical practices in the field entail is not always clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While research ethics considers principles such as confidentiality, privacy, and informed consent, a learning analytics project may not be considered &lt;em&gt;research&lt;/em&gt; at all (if its goal is not to produce generalizable knowledge). However, extensive collection of learning data, increasing cases of &amp;ldquo;black-box algorithms,&amp;rdquo; and more direct impact on learners necessitate some serious conversations about ethics in learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/7c/Blackbox3D-withGraphs.png&#34; alt=&#34;(Photo Credit: [Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_box))&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s discussions have already touched upon many questions about ethics. This week, we are going to dive into ethics, algorithmic accountability, and system integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-3-readings&#34;&gt;Week 3 Readings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prinsloo, P., &amp;amp; Slade, S. (2017). Ethics and Learning Analytics: Charting the (Un)Charted. In C. Lang, G. Siemens, A. Wise, &amp;amp; D. Gasevic (Eds.), Handbook of Learning Analytics (&lt;a href=&#34;https://solaresearch.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/chapter4.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4, pp. 49–57&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Society for Learning Analytics Research (SoLAR).  (Note: It may be difficult to highlight larger text snippets in this particular PDF file.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose one from the following two&lt;/strong&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitto, K., &amp;amp; Knight, S. (2019). Practical ethics for building learning analytics. British Journal of Educational Technology. &lt;strong&gt;Please annotate &lt;a href=&#34;http://sjgknight.com/finding-knowledge/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/EthicalLA-accepted_oro.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Open Access version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chen, B., &amp;amp; Zhu, H. (2019). Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design. Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Learning Analytics &amp;amp; Knowledge, 343–352.  &lt;strong&gt;Please annotate &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.08335.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Open Access version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading each article, &lt;strong&gt;please create at least 1 annotation and reply to 2 annotations made by peers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-learning-analytics-experts&#34;&gt;Meet Learning Analytics Experts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendistanceteachingandlearning.wordpress.com/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paul Prinsloo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the University of South Africa (Unisa) has been writing and giving talks about &amp;lsquo;ethics and learning analytics&amp;rsquo; for many years. He has recently delivered a keynote on this topic in Scotland. He has graciously allowed me to embed his slides on our course website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/prinsp/zombie-categories-broken-data-and-biased-algorithms-what-else-can-go-wrong-ethics-in-the-collection-analysis-and-use-of-student-data-111886874&#34; title=&#34;Zombie categories, broken data and biased algorithms: What else can go wrong? Ethics in the collection, analysis and use of student data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zombie categories, broken data and biased algorithms: What else can go wrong? Ethics in the collection, analysis and use of student data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/lJfMuY2tUK6WVI&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simon.buckinghamshum.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Simon Buckingham Shum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Director of the Connected Intelligence Centre (CIC) at the University of Technology Sydney, invited us to consider &amp;lsquo;Algorithmic Accountability&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Analytic System Integrity&amp;rsquo;. Discussion of Algorithmic Accountability has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acm.org/binaries/content/assets/public-policy/2017_usacm_statement_algorithms.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;taken up by important academic associations like the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)&lt;/a&gt;. But Simon stretches our thinking to consider &amp;lsquo;Analytic System Integrity&amp;rsquo; in learning analytics. Below is a talk he gave at the UCL Institute of Education in 2016. His team is recently working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://simon.buckinghamshum.net/2018/08/ethical-design-critique/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ethical Design Critique&lt;/a&gt;, which offers concrete measures to enhance ethics in learning analytics tools. (And he is scheduled to visit UMN this October! Details soon.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0t0IWvcO-Uo?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-with-learning-analytics&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Living&amp;rdquo; with Learning Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, we introduced &lt;a href=&#34;https://crowdlaaers.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CROWD LAAERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; designed for Hypothes.is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I encourage you to explore KF&amp;rsquo;s list of analytic tools (see below) that can be accessed via the &lt;strong&gt;Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; button. They are developed by colleagues from various countries. Note that we&amp;rsquo;re using the newest version of KF and colleagues are still revamping many of these analytic tools based on earlier versions. So they are not always user-friendly. If you have ideas that can make them better, consider turning your ideas into a course project and I will try to connect you with the right colleagues to realize your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/kf-analytic-tools.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;housekeeping&#34;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuing-to-consider-groups&#34;&gt;Continuing to Consider Groups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please continue to explore and articulate your Working Group project ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; Please consider &lt;em&gt;problems/goals&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;stakeholders&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;data sources&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;analysis&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;action&lt;/em&gt; of your project. Continue to comment on each other&amp;rsquo;s ideas on KF and don&amp;rsquo;t be shy about saying &amp;ldquo;Our ideas are like cousins. Let&amp;rsquo;s team up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please start to consider which Special Interest Group(s) you&amp;rsquo;re interested in.&lt;/strong&gt; Below is a list of tentative topics but you can suggest topics beyond the list. Ideally, the Special Interest Group you sign up for is related to your Working Group project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Network Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive Models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text and Discourse Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Learning Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Institutional Readiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- **Finally, whenever there is any interesting article, please either annotate using Hypothesis or share via Slack.** --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.basised.com/scottsdale/files/2018/02/adios-gif-tumblr-10.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-meeting&#34;&gt;Virtual Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next virtual meeting will take place on &lt;strong&gt;Monday, 09/23, 5-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; via Zoom. You will receive a Calendar invitation with details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Learning Analytics: A Brief Overview</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the engaged conversations in the first week of #LAUMN!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in such thoughtful dialogues via Hypothes.is, Slack, and Zoom. As we try to survive all those acronyms, here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/glossary/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a community glossary&lt;/a&gt; you can look at and contribute to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is apparent to myself is that the breadth of expertise represented in our community is truly energizing. I hope we can continue to have deep conversations &lt;em&gt;within and beyond this community&lt;/em&gt;, and to engage in learning that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; to everyone of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of &amp;ldquo;living and exploring the capacity of learning analytics&amp;rdquo; (see the Syllabus), I want to introduce an analytics tool named &lt;a href=&#34;https://crowdlaaers.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CROWD LAAERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; developed by my UC-Denver colleagues &lt;strong&gt;Remi Kalir&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Francisco Perez&lt;/strong&gt; for the Marginal Syllabus project. This application, which just came out last year, retrieves annotations from the server and generates interesting interactive visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, after authenticating yourself using your &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/account/developer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is API token&lt;/a&gt;, you will be able to choose our group and have a bird-eye view of our annotation activities. I found the &lt;code&gt;Threads&lt;/code&gt; section quite useful for discovering threads with more (or less) participation. You can click on a particular thread to filter the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/crowdlaaers-2019.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example is the calendar view that tells us when we tend to make annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/crowdlaaers-2019-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears we were quite busy making annotations during the weekend. I believe we can do better next week &amp;ndash; working less during the weekend if possible ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/13HBDT4QSTpveU/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-2&#34;&gt;Week 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a stronger grasp of the field of LA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to explore Working Group project ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading and discussing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Siemens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Siemens&lt;/a&gt; (2013) article during Week 1, it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile to watch a lecture George gave to a MOOC (massive open online course) on learning analytics. George is the founding president of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Society for Learning Analytics Research (SoLAR)&lt;/a&gt;, which is the most prominent international organization of learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KqETXdq68vY?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Great questioning during Week 1 on whether the definition(s) of learning analytics have changed over the years. I encourage you to keep this question alive as we dig into more readings, interact with scholars like George on Twitter, or tweet such questions to the #LearningAnalytics hashtag.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we will get a chance to take a closer look at this field by exploring more cases/examples and posing more questions. What problems do learning analytics seek to address? In which educational settings? At which levels of an education system? Because this field is truly inter- and trans-disciplinary, I expect us to enter this field from our unique backgrounds and contribute to the field with different perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buckingham Shum, S. (2012). &lt;a href=&#34;https://iite.unesco.org/pics/publications/en/files/3214711.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UNESCO Policy Brief: Learning Analytics&lt;/a&gt;. UNESCO Institute for Information Technologies in Education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose one from below&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Note: #1 is open-access, and #2 is accessible to UMN colleagues&lt;/em&gt;):

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bienkowski, M., Feng, M., &amp;amp; Means, B. (2012). &lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.ed.gov/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/edm-la-brief.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enhancing Teaching and Learning Through Educational Data Mining and Learning Analytics: An issue brief&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(pp. 1-35)&lt;/strong&gt;. U.S. Department of Education Office of Educational Technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krumm, A., Means, B., &amp;amp; Bienkowski, M. (2018). Learning Analytics Goes to School: A Collaborative Approach to Improving Education, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=1LB5J1UytIV2yOq47xKFrnneTJ7YCMJQV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Routledge.  (&lt;em&gt;Note: This reading can only be annotated offline. Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZW6L-0qkwI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; to learn how.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading each article, &lt;strong&gt;please create at least 1 annotation and reply to 2 annotations made by peers&lt;/strong&gt;. Let the community know when you find a case that matches perfectly with your interests, stretches your imagination of learning analytics, or concerns you for whatever reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I encourage you to &lt;strong&gt;be very intentional about tags&lt;/strong&gt; you use in Hypothesis annotations. Several ground rules I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose to our collective tagging to help us better index our ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s include &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; in our tags (e.g., &lt;code&gt;#question&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use lowercase (e.g., &lt;code&gt;#sharing&lt;/code&gt;), unless the tag is a named entity (e.g., &lt;code&gt;#LMS&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not include spaces, but use underscore (&lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt;) instead (e.g., &lt;code&gt;#data_mining&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;#data mining&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reminder&lt;/strong&gt;: If you are a UMN participant, when annotating with Hypothes.is, please make sure the LAUMN-2019 group is selected.  If you are not sure about annotating PDFs, please refer back to tutorials in Week 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploring-working-group-project-ideas&#34;&gt;Exploring Working Group project ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://thumbs.gfycat.com/MistyWeirdHyrax-size_restricted.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Source: https://gfycat.com/gifs/detail/mistyweirdhyrax&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While/after reading, draft a project idea based on your interests and post it on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kf6.us/login&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Knowledge Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. At this point, it is totally okay if your project idea is more or less vague. This is an opportunity for us to learn more about our interests, receive feedback, and form project teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After posting your project idea, please read and build on each other&amp;rsquo;s contributions if you&amp;rsquo;re also interested or have questions/suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure how to create or build on a Knowledge Forum contribution, watch this video tutorial (note the UI may look different as we&amp;rsquo;re using a more recent version of the software):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g-SorK8XFeQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!-- For open participants, please tweet a blog post (or a shared Google doc) using the #LAUMN hashtag.  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip&lt;/strong&gt;: In Knowledge Forum, you will see a searchable list of Hypothesis annotations from our community. You can either drag an annotation to form a new note, or drag an annotation into an existing note. You can use this feature if your project idea is grounded in the readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Below are a list of example project ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; Please see the syllabus for more detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying Natural Language Processing to Investigating Language Development and Epistemic Complexity in Group Chats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating a Teacher Dashboard in K-12: A Mixed-Methods Study of Teacher Perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Burn the World&amp;rdquo; Learning Analytics Design (&lt;em&gt;Note: Burn the World is a game for environmental education.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Bridge&amp;rdquo;: An Analytics Tool to Integrate Community Knowledge on StackOverflow in RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a Deep Learning Model for the Prediction of Student Success in Introductory Physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-meeting&#34;&gt;Virtual Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; meet synchronously this week. Our next virtual meeting will take place on &lt;strong&gt;Monday, 09/23, 5-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; via Zoom. You will receive a Calendar invitation with details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A warm welcome to &lt;strong&gt;CI 5371 - Learning Analytics: Theory and Practice&lt;/strong&gt;! I am so excited to offer this course again this fall at the University of Minnesota. As the instructor, I learn so much from the class community each year and look forward to our adventure together this semester!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get familiar with the course, including its design, schedule, and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to know each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read an introductory article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss our diverse interests in learning analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-course&#34;&gt;The Course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing first, please read &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/laumn-2019-syl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the course syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in its entirety. Leave a comment or send me an email when you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-setup&#34;&gt;Technology setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An online course does not need to be about watching videos and answering quizzes. To foster rich learning experiences, we will be using several technological tools to foster social, collaborative learning. Depending on your familiarity with these tools, there could be a learning curve. So please spend time this week to familiarize yourself with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoom&lt;/strong&gt;. We will host a number of virtual meetings on Zoom throughout the semester. Please make sure your computer has &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; installed (see the video below). Please test your Zoom setup in advance to make sure audio and video configurations work properly. You will receive a calendar invitation with details about joining our Zoom meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vFhAEoCF7jg?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack&lt;/strong&gt;. You will receive a link that invites you to join &lt;a href=&#34;https://la-mn.slack.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our Slack community&lt;/a&gt;. Course announcements are made on Slack. All sorts of class discussion will take place there as well. You can also interact with course alums in some public channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time using Slack? Watch the video below and/or read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/115004071768-What-is-Slack-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;brief introduction to Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9RJZMSsH7-g?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/strong&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re a formal participant, you should have received a link that invites you to join our Hypothes.is group. Hypothes.is is a web annotation tool that enables us to discuss readings in a contextual manner. When annotating, please make sure our group name (&lt;strong&gt;LAUMN-2019&lt;/strong&gt;) is properly selected. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/help/quick-start-guide/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; to get started, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/help/annotating-with-groups/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; to learn about annotating together as a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://d242fdlp0qlcia.cloudfront.net/uploads/2018/03/21135305/scopeselector-groupname.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Forum&lt;/strong&gt; (KF). If you&amp;rsquo;re a formal participant, you should have received a link and a registration key to join our Knowledge Forum community. KF is a space for collaborative knowledge building. It&amp;rsquo;s where we propose our initial (and sometimes naive) ideas and then grow them this semester. KF has a suite of analytics tools as well, so it will allows us to &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; the capacity of learning analytics while we explore this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ebgi-NnjSak&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-tracks-of-participation&#34;&gt;Two tracks of participation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course website is openly available, allowing two tracks of participation designed for this class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UMN class&lt;/strong&gt;: For UMN graduate students enrolled in the class, your participation in this class is not that different from taking another online class. You are expected to meet course requirements outlined in the course syllabus. You will have &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; spaces (on Slack and Hypothesis private group) for within-class communications. You can decide the extent to which you interact with colleagues outside of the class list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open participation&lt;/strong&gt;: For &amp;lsquo;Open Participants&amp;rsquo; who would like to follow along, you can access the same materials curated on this website. Because 90% of course readings are open-access, you will be able to annotate readings using Hypothes.is as well (using &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=tag%3ALAUMN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;LAUMN&lt;/code&gt; tag&lt;/a&gt;). You are also encouraged to interact with me and community members via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23LAUMN&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter hashtag &lt;code&gt;#LAUMN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback on the design, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-1&#34;&gt;Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course syllabus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.sagepub.com.ezp3.lib.umn.edu/doi/pdf/10.1177/0002764213498851&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Siemens, G. (2013). Learning analytics: The emergence of a discipline. The American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1380–1400.&lt;/a&gt;  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://iu.instructure.com/files/56153619/download?download_frd=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Downloadable PDF&lt;/a&gt; for Open Participants.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading Siemens (2013), &lt;strong&gt;please create at least 1 annotation and reply to 2 annotations made by peers&lt;/strong&gt;. Not sure what/how to annotate, consider sentence starters like: &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;m intrigued by...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;m surprised by...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;I need to understand...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Additional resource...&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Click on the Annotations link to the top of this page to see all annotations posted to our Hypothes.is group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-meeting&#34;&gt;Virtual Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first virtual meeting will take place on &lt;strong&gt;Monday, 09/09, 5-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; via Zoom. You will receive a Calendar invitation with details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotations</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://hypothes.is/groups/a3ZVxWe8/laumn-2019&#34; width = &#34;100%&#34; height = &#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
