<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weekly Pages on CI 5371</title>
    <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weekly Pages on CI 5371</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (CC BY)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Hidden Assumptions: Epistemology, Pedagogy, and Assessment</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week5/</guid>
      <description>In this week, we will extend our dialogues on learning theory in Week 4 into deeper conversations about hidden assumptions in learning analytics.
This line of thinking has been greatly informed by a talk given by Simon Knight at LAK13 titled Epistemology, Pedagogy, Assessment and Learning Analytics (see slides below). Their work has evolved over the years and one reading for this week is a book chapter with a set of provocations pushing us to think more about hidden assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Theory and Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>Learning analytics are about learning, so theories of learning should not be ditched despite the data deluge that has been fueling the growth of learning analytics. Since the dawn of the field, there have been voices arguing for the importance of learning theory in the design, development, and implementation of learning analytics. In 2015, a special section was published by the Journal of Learning Analytics on the relation between learning theory and learning analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Ethics, Algorithmic Accountability, and System Integrity</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s be clear, ethics should not be an after-thought in a learning analytics application. But what do ethical practices in the field entail is not always clear.
While research ethics considers principles such as confidentiality, privacy, and informed consent, a learning analytics project may not be considered research at all (if its goal is not to produce generalizable knowledge). However, expansive collection of learning data, increasing cases of &amp;ldquo;black-box algorithms,&amp;rdquo; and more direct impact on learners necessitate some serious conversations about ethics in learning analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Learning Analytics: A Brief Overview</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for the engaged conversations in the first week of #LAUMN!
We&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in such thoughtful dialogues via Hypothes.is annotations. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to survive all those acronyms by maintaining a community glossary. Also a big shout-out to Crystal Rose-Wainstock for her #LAUMN tweet about ethics in learning analytics (below). The breadth of expertise represented in our community is truly energizing. I hope we can continue to have deep conversations within and beyond this community, and to engage in learning that&amp;rsquo;s personal to everyone of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/glossary/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>A warm welcome to CI 5371 - Learning Analytics: Theory and Practice! This course has been taught twice by myself at the University of Minnesota (in 2015 and 2016). This is the first time this course is offered fully online as a formal (non-special topics) course. As the instructor, I look forward to our adventure together this semester!
This week we will:
 Get familiar with the course, including its design, schedule, and tools Get to know each other Read an introductory article Discuss our diverse interests in learning analytics  The Course Syllabus First thing first, please read the course syllabus (http://bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotations</title>
      <link>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colig.github.io/laumn/post/annotations/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>